congratulations on making it to this
point this has been one of the tightest
races in the history of this competition
but this week everything changes there
will be no more veteran artists
returning making you the strongest eight
artists ever to fight for the title now
must battle each other and only one of
you will win $100,000 a feature in Inked
Magazine and the title of ink master
five of you have been to a finale before
this whole group sitting here is finale
material one mistake you're out this is
the time to really turn it up this is it
be the best today there will be no flash
challenge we are moving directly into
the next elimination tattoo Wow you're
being judged on texture texture is a way
of making a piece of art look like you
could run your finger over and feel how
it feels in real life for this
elimination tattoo you must completely
transform your canvases back giving them
a full set of wings oh and you must
collaborate with another artist Oh two
of you must tattooed the same canvas at
the same time one artist was tattoo a
good wing on half of your canvases back
and the other artist must tattoo an evil
wing on the other half me
we must work together to give your
canvas a cohesive tattoo but you'll be
judged individually these canvases have
no clue what the hell they're in for
I hope they brought some rawhide shoes
because this is gonna be painful let's
meet your canvases
clean you won the best tattoo of the day
in the last elimination tattoo you now
have the power to assign the canvases
that means you will also determine which
artists are working together so choose
wisely I feel like a mad dog on a leash
and I'm about to bite anybody that gets
in my way you want to get some wings on
your back yeah I was thinking good one I
would want native feathers not fluffy
angelic and the evil being more dragon
like claws at the top claws whoever
you're paired with will make her break
this tattoos I don't want to get teamed
up with Jesse because the last time we
got teamed up we've lost and lost big
what are you thinking really open to see
what the artist has in mind I was
thinking the good wing being whimsical
very like and then the evil side being
burned and crow like with some bones
coming out of it hmm
whatever cleen has skull picks it's a
complete crapshoot nobody knows what
he's gonna do
he doesn't understand strategy
canvases one by one please read the
artist's name on the bottom of your
skull Christian and Maddie I'm stoked to
be paired with Christian we have an
alliance clean is a moron Jesse
sausage
who looks like clean actually has a
brain after all these two ups so bad
last time obviously they're gonna screw
up again cleen Rock one James me and
clean are the fastest tattooers in this
competition if this person wanted a full
back piece there you go you gonna have a
back piece Jimmy
Anthony up to you to decide which artist
tattoos good and which artist tattoos
evil but once the tattoo starts you
cannot switch and this week there will
be no human canvas jury all the
decisions are completely up to the
judges you will have six hours to give
your canvas a full set of wings good
luck
pleasure to meet you right up here so
we're gonna do one kind of baddie
medieval dragon ish and the other one
kind of Native American today these
tattooers have to do a back piece
basically on their canvases a Raven's
wing would be the bad side and then the
good side we were thinking more fairy
butterfly this is tough because they
have to match sides one side has to be
evil one side has to be good you have a
specific side that you're leaning
towards the angelic side about that size
but the actual sizes and composition
should flow together how's that on mine
look big enough our dude he's a big guy
I picked that for myself cuz I'm a man
and I'm here to go big or go home just
trying to get a pretty good size tattoo
impressive I hope this do can handle two
dudes at once man because you're getting
a 12-hour tattoo in six hours the pain
is excruciating you better make sure you
eat then just try and get in the food
coma it's gonna be brutal man
we could do normal Raven wing and fairy
wing or whatever in my opinion a little
boring the other idea that I have I
really like the concept of butterfly bat
wings just making sure that we can knock
this out in six hours to feel like I
could do something like this in about
six hours I feel it's a lot it's a lot
just these ideas are always crazy now is
the time for bulletproof and simple
well I'd let's why I want to see your
idea because I mean it might be
different than what I'm seeing in my
head I want to do creative tattoos I I
do too
but because we're gonna be partners in
this and I know that we're being judged
separately I think we should just dial
it back so that we know that we don't
put her through a bunch of trauma teas
sausage and Jesse's you're not feeling
it I can tell you
okay artists you have six hours to show
texture by giving your canvas wings and
your time begins now let's give this
done salon the crazy part about this
challenge is it have to work in pairs on
one canvas so while they're competing
against each other they also have to
work together to make their wings
cohesive right about the same spot
pretty good there's a lot of
difficulties with two people tattooing
one person at the same time which
reporter Bobby so just gonna go downward
okay there's a lot of push and pull and
give and take you have to work together
so that you don't screw each other up in
the process
on the same page keep the milk
luckily I've done a lot of tandem pieces
Maddie and I are gonna take the same
wing flip it I'm gonna make mine really
soft white and angelic yeah you're going
pretty good Maddie can take his rat it
out and make it look like it fallen
angel wing
that's just on fire spot over here yeah
it's a lot of work at once we probably
are the biggest one our design that
we're doing is very elaborate it's a lot
of work on someone's body and it's short
amount of time no matter what mana pain
that she's in we're gonna coach her
through it there's no way in hell that
we're not finishing this tattoo things
are a little rocky
Jimmy wipes very very aggressive I'm
having to hold her down and fight
against him
yeah I'm very clean and I'm very precise
in my tattoo that's almost impossible
right now I'm afraid that I might not
finish really three hours to go
pick something that was
one side is super big and other side
this our tattoo is huge this thing is
the biggest baddest tattoo that's ever
been done on ink master pretty much
getting the full back piece my strategy
on this tattoo is mow it down nobody's
got the balls to go this big and I
guarantee that I'm just trying to shade
plants but look cohesive in the thought
process we're doing dark from the side
over here looks good cuz you got the
texture on your side I'm trying to keep
it smooth rolling into yours
woo I'm stuck me and clean we got this
thing this fool is gonna jump off the
damn table and start flying away I did
everybody go so strong it better be some
bells and whistles on up hello y'all
screw things out on anybody out there
dude y'all got the kitchen sink in there
sausage nothing as small as hell let me
pull out the periscope it's not a tattoo
over there now see it's a stiff
competition
there okay I feel like I'm swimming in
quicksand
with everybody's boot in the house on my
forehead it sucks
sausage can I get a few seconds yeah go
ahead tattooing with a partner on the
same body is like trying to write
perfect calligraphy in a car that's
driving down a rocky road in the middle
of a snowstorm I mean it's really
causing me to not really get into a
rhythm to tattoo what I'm just trying to
see how you're doing is sausage is
stressing me out I'm trying to figure
out texture and don't want to put too
much to text your challenge you don't
want to not put too much sausage pull it
together come on man
three two one that is it typed up scenes
down no more ink
oh my god the feathers look awesome oh
dude those oil jobs Jessie looks like a
good wine texture back cleen's tattoo is
huge but it has no texture tons of wonky
lines and a whole bottle full of white
just popped in there this knucklehead
thinks that everything is about bigger
it's not about bigger it's about better
clean
to run the st. page and keep them real
smelly luckily I've done a lot of tandem
peace